A Guide to the Kolbe Family Papers, 1886-2014
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Kolbe Family Papers, 1886-2014
The Library of Virginia
51777
1.2 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of J. Christian Kolbe, Richmond.
Biographical Information
John George Kolbe was born on 11 October 1886. He married Ruby Royal Penick (1898-1976) on 5 November 1921. They resided in Richmond, Virginia, where he sold gas ranges, gas hot water heaters, and other kitchen equipment and supplies. They had four children. He died in Richmond on 23 May 1953 and is buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1886-2014, of the Kolbe family of Richmond, Virginia, namely John George Kolbe (1886-1953) and his wife Ruby Royal (Penick) Kolbe (1898-1976). Much of the correspondence relates to the health issues of their two infant sons, the medical care they received at Jefferson Hospital in Philadelphia, and the subsequent death of John G. Kolbe, Jr. (1922-1924) while there. The collection also includes accounts and receipts, baptismal and confirmation certificates, greeting cards, photographs, programs, will of Emily Loeffler (1856-1936), and a WWI induction order.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1921. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1923. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1924 (February). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1924 (March). (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1924 (April-August)). (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1928. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1929. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1930. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1934. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1944. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1947. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, undated. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Accounts and Receipts. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Addresses. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Baptismal Certificate. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Boy Scouts. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Burial Vault. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Clippings. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Confirmation Certificate. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Greeting Cards. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Laburnum Elementary School, 1957-1958. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- New Store Opening, June 1924. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Penick, Ruby - School Record. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Photograph Album. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Photographs. (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- Photographs (Oversize). (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Programs. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ritual of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- St. John's Evangelical Lutheran Church. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Sauer's Monument Avenue Gardens. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Wedding, 5 November 1921. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Will of Emily Loeffler. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- WWI Induction Order. (Box 2, Folder 10)